Guide to the Woolsey Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1664-(1818-1889) 1950; Series I; 13.5 linear feet (32 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Included in this series is the correspondence of various members of the Woolsey family, but primarily that of Theodore Dwight Woolsey and Theodore Salisbury Woolsey. Correspondence has been arranged chronologically with the unidentified letters placed at the end of the series.
  - 1664-1750, 1756-1758 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1760-1762, 1764-1765, 1768-1770, 1772 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1773-1780, 1782-1784 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    General note
    (includes documents re Benjamin Woolsey estate)
  - 1785-1793, 1797-1799, 1800 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1802-1805, 1806-1809, 1811-1812 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1813-1815 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1816-1817 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1818
    - January - December (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - 1819 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1820
    - January - December (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - 1821
    - January - December (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
      See also: box 1, folder 1
  - 1822
    - January - July (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
    - August - December (Box 2, Folder 19-21)
    - miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1823
    - January-December (Box 2, Folder 23-26)
  - 1824
    - January-Feb, May-August (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - September-December (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1825
    - January (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - April - September (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
    - February-March (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - November-December (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1826
    - January-March (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - April-May, July-Sep, November-December (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 1827
    - Jan, March-May (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - June-December (Box 3, Folder 37-39)
  - 1828
    - January-December (Box 3, Folder 40-45)
    - Letterbook, letters from Sarah Dwight Woolsey to H.C. Beach, 1828-1835 (Box 3A, Folder 45a)
  - 1829
    - January-December (Box 4, Folder 46-54)
  - 1830
    - January-December (Box 4, Folder 55-58)
  - 1831
    - January-December (Box 4, Folder 59-61)
    - miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - 1832
    - January-December (Box 5, Folder 63-68)
    - miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - 1833
    - January-December (Box 5, Folder 70-76)
    - miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - 1834
    - January-July (Box 5, Folder 78-81)
    - August-December (Box 6, Folder 82-84)
    - miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - 1835
    - January-December (Box 6, Folder 86-90)
  - 1836
    - January-December (Box 6, Folder 91-95)
    - miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - 1837
    - January-December (Box 7, Folder 97-102)
    - miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - 1838
    - January-December (Box 7, Folder 104-107)
    - miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - 1839
    - January-December (Box 7, Folder 109-115)
    - miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 116)
  - 1840
    - January-December (Box 8, Folder 117-121)
    - miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - 1841
    - January-December (Box 8, Folder 123-125)
  - 1842
    - January-December (Box 8, Folder 126-133)
    - miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - 1843
    - January-December (Box 9, Folder 135-140)
    - miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 141)
  - 1844
    - January-December (Box 9, Folder 142-149)
  - 1845
    - January-December (Box 10, Folder 150-157)
    - miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - 1846
    - January-December (Box 10, Folder 159-165)
    - miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 166)
  - 1847
    - January-December (Box 11, Folder 167-174)
    - miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 175)
  - 1848
    - January-December (Box 11, Folder 176-182)
  - 1849
    - January-December (Box 12, Folder 183-187)
    - miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 188)
  - 1850
    - January-December (Box 12, Folder 189-192)
  - 1851
    - January-December (Box 12, Folder 193-199)
    - miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 200)
  - 1852
    - January-December (Box 13, Folder 201-208)
    - miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 209)
  - 1853
    - January-December (Box 13, Folder 210-217)
    - miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 218)
  - 1854
    - January-December (Box 14, Folder 219-230)
    - miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 231)
  - 1855
    - January-December (Box 14, Folder 232-235)
    - miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 236)
  - 1856
    - January-December (Box 15, Folder 237-238)
  - 1857
    - January-April (Box 15, Folder 239-240)
    - August (Box 15, Folder 241)
    - May-July (Box 15, Folder 242-243)
    - September-December (Box 15, Folder 244-246)
  - 1858
    - January-December (Box 15, Folder 247-257)
    - miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 258)
  - 1859
    - January - November 22 (Box 16, Folder 259-269)
    - December (Box 16, Folder 270)
    - miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 271)
  - 1860
    - January - June 1-12 (Box 16, Folder 272-277)
    - June 14 - December (Box 16, Folder 278-284)
  - 1861
    - January-December (Box 17, Folder 285-296)
    - miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 297)
  - 1862
    - January (Box 17, Folder 298)
    - February (Box 17, Folder 299)
    - March 1-15, 17-31 (Box 17, Folder 300)
    - April 1-14, 19-30 (Box 17, Folder 301)
    - May 3-15, 20-30 (Box 17, Folder 302)
    - June 1-16, 18-30 (Box 17, Folder 303)
    - July-December (Box 18, Folder 304-312)
  - 1863
    - January-December (Box 18, Folder 313-324)
    - miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 325)
  - 1864
    - January-December (Box 19, Folder 326-339)
  - 1865
    - January-December (Box 19, Folder 340-349)
  - 1866
    - January-December (Box 20, Folder 350-361)
    - miscellaneous (Box 20, Folder 362)
  - 1867
    - January-December (Box 20, Folder 363-375)
  - 1868
    - January-November (Box 21, Folder 376-382)
  - 1869
    - January-December (Box 21, Folder 383-396)
  - 1870
    - January-August 21-31 (Box 22, Folder 397-419)
    - September-December (Box 23, Folder 420-429)
  - 1871
    - January-April 30 (Box 23, Folder 430-439)
    - May-December (Box 24, Folder 440-449)
    - miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 450)
  - 1872
    - January-December (Box 24, Folder 451-460)
  - 1873
    - January-December (Box 25, Folder 461-468)
    - miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 469)
  - 1874
    - January-December (Box 25, Folder 470-482)
  - 1875
    - January-December (Box 26, Folder 483-490)
    - miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 491)
  - 1876
    - January-December (Box 26, Folder 492-503)
  - 1877
    - January-December (Box 27, Folder 504-516)
    - miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 517)
  - 1878
    - January-July (Box 27, Folder 518-522)
    - October-December (Box 27, Folder 523-528)
  - 1879
    - January-December (Box 28, Folder 529-538)
  - 1880
    - January-June (Box 28, Folder 539-546)
    - June miscellaneous (Box 28, Folder 547)
    - July-December (Box 28, Folder 548-552)
  - 1881
    - January 1-15 (Box 29, Folder 553)
    - January 17-31 (Box 29, Folder 554)
    - February-June (Box 29, Folder 555-561)
    - June miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 562)
    - July-December (Box 29, Folder 563-570)
  - 1882
    - January-April (Box 29, Folder 571-578)
    - May-December (Box 30, Folder 579-586)
    - miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 587)
  - 1883
    - January-December (Box 30, Folder 588-592)
  - 1884
    - January-December (Box 30, Folder 593-600)
  - 1885
    - January-December (Box 30, Folder 601-605)
  - 1886
    - January-December (Box 31, Folder 606-608)
  - 1887-1888 (Box 31, Folder 609-610)
  - 1889
    - January-December (Box 31, Folder 611-614)
    - miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 615)
  - 1890-1899 (Box 31, Folder 616-617)
  - 1900-1902, 1904-1905, 1907-1908 (Box 31, Folder 618)
  - 1909-1910, 1912-1913 (Box 31, Folder 619)
  - Yale University Athletic Committee: 1897-1910 (Box 31, Folder 619A)
  - 1914
    - January-December (Box 31, Folder 620-623)
    - miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 624)
  - 1915-1921 (Box 31, Folder 625-629)
  - 1923-1924, 1926-1928, 1929-1941, 1945-1950 (Box 31, Folder 630)
  - undated, (A-1) (Box 32, Folder 631)
  - undated, (J-P, Pa-Pq) (Box 32, Folder 632)
  - undated, (Pr-Prichard, A-Ellen) (Box 32, Folder 633)
  - undated, (Prichard, Ellen) (Box 32, Folder 634)
  - undated, (Prichard, Ellen-Ez) (Box 32, Folder 635)
  - undated, (Prichard, F-Z, Pz) (Box 32, Folder 636)
  - undated, (Q-V) (Box 32, Folder 637)
  - undated, (Wa-Woolsey, A-Martha) (Box 32, Folder 638)
  - undated, (Woolsey, Mary-Z-Z) (Box 32, Folder 639)
  - undated, unsigned (Box 32, Folder 640)
- Theodore Dwight Woolsey Writings, 1811-1889; Series II; 5.5 linear feet (14 boxes)
  The Theodore Dwight Woolsey Writings consist of both manuscript and printed articles, essays, lectures, sermons, translations, and notes. In addition, there are newspaper clippings, reports, and a few essays and articles written by others which were of interest to Woolsey.
  The series is divided by subject matter into a number of sub-sections which are as follows: The series is divided by subject matter into a number of sub-sections which are as follows:
  1. General: miscellaneous articles, lectures, and notes on a variety of topics, many of them written while a student at Yale College
  2. Biographical: biographical essays written by Woolsey
  3. Divorce: notes, articles, lectures, sermons, and newsclippings on the subject of divorce in the United States.
  4. Greek Grammar: manuscript notes and an article on Greek grammar.
  5. Greek Literature: essays, notes, and lectures on Greek literature.
  6. Greek notebooks: bound notebooks pertaining to various topics on Greek grammar and literature; the note-books also contain some of Woolsey's financial accounts.
  7. Paganism and Polytheism: manuscript articles and essays, and a complete lecture series, including printed programs, on paganism and polytheism, incorporating Woolsey's research into the mythology of the ancient Near East as well as Greek and Biblical material.
  8. Biblical: Biblical writings, listed by order of the Old and New Testament books, contains exegesis, commentary, and syntactical analysis. In addition, there are critical notes and essays, notably those written for the Sunday School Times, covering the complete books of Mark and Acts.
  9. Theological: essays, lectures, notes, and prayers on a variety of theological topics, such as the authority of Scriptures, the relations of Church and state, and problems in moral philosophy.
  10. Bible Revision: Woolsey's annotated, printed copies of the translations of the Bible, which were circulated among the members of the Bible Revision Committee. The series also includes the printed correspondence and resolutions of both the American and British divisions of the Committee.
  11. Sermons: Woolsey's sermons are arranged by order of Old and New Testament books, from which the text of the sermon is taken. Each listing notes the text and date of the sermon.
  12. History: this section is listed alphabetically either by title or subject, and includes materials pertaining to European, Greek, and Reformation history. In addition, there is a general section containing Woolsey's reflections and lectures on the major themes in history and civilization.
  13. International Law: contains Woolsey's writings on International Law, including papers on international disputes, arbitration, naval problems, war, and neutrality. The lectures and articles on treaties have been arranged alphabetically by the location of the treaty convention. Additional material, under the rubric of Rights and State, contains Woolsey's writings on the respective rights and duties of the citizens and of the state, and various aspects of political philosophy.
  - General
    - Brothers Society Decisions, notes when a student, 1819 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - "Geography of Isles", 1811(?) (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - "Honor", 1850 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - "Honor and Political Life", 1875 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Kingsley's Lectures notes when a student, 1819 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Latin Oration and assorted notes, undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - "Moral Statistics of the U.S", 1881 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Reform: "Address to the People", Reform Conference, N.Y., 1882, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Resolutions of the National Civil Service Reform League.
    - Universities and colleges, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Welker's Lectures on Mythology, 1828 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - "Women in Modern Civilization", 1855 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Yale College
    - Class record book and anonymous paper on William the Conqueror (probably a student's), undated (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Historical discourse, 1850 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - notes on governance; purchase of Stiles portrait, 1855, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Yale Law School, Historical Discourse on, 1874 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Commemoretion Address, notes, (1851!) (Box 33, Folder 16a)
  - Biographical
    - Bacon, Leonard, Circa1882 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Edwards, Jonathan, 1870 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Pritchard, (Gilman), 1823, undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
      including Pritchard's membership diploma in the Bunker Hill Monument Association
    - Silliman, Benjamin, 1864 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Divorce
    - Constitutional Reform, 1881, 1883 (Box 33, Folder 21)
      MSS notes & printed
    - Divorce Evil--report of the General Conference of Maine, G.S. Dickerman, chairman, 1883 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - "Family and Divorce" by Rev. E.P. Stone, 1884 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Historical background and precedents, 1881 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Law and practice of divorce in U.S., 1881 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Newsclippings, 1881 (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Sermons and Biblical Studies, 1881 (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Statistics: foreign countries and United States, Circa 1881 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Greek Grammar
    - "Eis, single and prefixed", undated (Box 34, Folder 29)
    - Hermann's Rule, examples contradicting, undated (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Greek Literature
    - Aeschylus, "Prometheus Bound" and Sophocles, "Electra" with notes (signed by Edith Woolsey), undated (Box 34, Folder 31)
    - Amphictyonic Council, Isocrates, Ajax, pronunciation, undated (Box 34, Folder 32)
    - Bactyli, or sacred stones, undated (Box 34, Folder 33)
    - Commentaries on unidentified works, undated (Box 34, Folder 34)
    - "The Electra of Sophocles", undated (Box 34, Folder 34a)
    - History of Greek Literature, undated (Box 34, Folder 35)
    - "Kronos", undated (Box 34, Folder 36)
    - "notes on Pindar", 1843 (Box 34, Folder 36a)
    - "Origin and Progress of the Greek Mythical System", undated (Box 34, Folder 37)
    - Orphic Poets, undated (Box 34, Folder 38)
    - Poetic meter and measures, undated (Box 34, Folder 39)
    - Plato, lecture on, before a popular audience, undated (Box 34, Folder 40)
    - Sophocles' Oedipus Tyrannus: observations, undated (Box 34, Folder 41)
    - Theocraciae, undated (Box 34, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 34, Folder 43)
  - Greek notebooks
    - Greek syntax and verbs; Greek citizenship, civil rights, 1830 (Box 35, Folder 43a)
    - The Dionysia, undated (Box 35, Folder 43b)
    - Contemporaries of Demosthenes, poems, financial accounts, 1830, undated (Box 35, Folder 43c)
    - Homeric Question, epic cycles, And financial accounts, 1838, circa 1870-1882 (Box 35, Folder 43)
  - Paganism and Polytheism
    - Finnish-Castren Mythology, undated (Box 36, Folder 44)
    - Magic and Divination, 1887 (Box 36, Folder 45)
    - Monotheism and Polytheism, 1871, undated (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - Rise of Polytheism, undated (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Worship of Heavenly Bodies, undated (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - Lecture Series, Circa1880-1887
      - Programs for Two Series, printed, undated (Box 36, Folder 50)
      - I-II Origins, developments, changes, and decay, undated (Box 36, Folder 51)
      - III Relations of Polytheism and Monotheism; Worship, undated (Box 36, Folder 52)
      - IV Classification of deities, traces of monotheism, undated (Box 36, Folder 53)
      - V Secondary objects of worship (Box 36, Folder 53)
      - VI Religious mythology (Box 36, Folder 54)
      - VII Interpretations of Religious myths (Box 36, Folder 54)
      - VIII Worship: priests, idolatry, acrifices (Box 36, Folder 55)
      - 1X Decline of Paganism in the Roman Empire (Box 36, Folder 55)
      - X Moral influences of Heathenism; comparison with Judaism; general estimates of higher pagan religions (Box 36, Folder 56)
      - XI Monotheism in the Hebrew Scriptures (Box 36, Folder 56)
  - Biblical
    - "Chinese Equivalent for our word 'God' ", and Chinese translation of the Bible, undated (Box 36, Folder 57)
    - New Covenant: Hebrew viii, 8-13 and Jer iii, 31-34, undated (Box 36, Folder 58)
    - Psalms, Proverbs, notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 59)
    - Minor prophets, notes on Hebrew syntax. (Also outline of world history, list of painters), undated (Box 37, Folder 60)
    - Job, Lamentations; Hebrew etymology; Jewish geneologies, undated (Box 37, Folder 61)
    - Kingdom of God in the New Testament, undated (Box 37, Folder 62)
    - "Nonnus: His Expression for.. .", n.d (Box 37, Folder 63)
    - Mark: Critical notes and commentary, 1882 (Box 37, Folder 64)
    - John, authorship of Gospel; MSS lecture, printed article, 1883, 1884 (Box 37, Folder 65)
    - "Acts, Introduction to the Study of", 1882 (Box 37, Folder 66)
    - Acts 1-14: Critical notes, 1882-1884 (Box 37, Folder 67)
    - Acts 15-28: Critical notes, 1884-1885 (Box 37, Folder 68)
    - Acts XV, 17-18, XXVI 28-29, XXVII 17, exegetical notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 69)
    - Rom iii 20-31, Critical notes, Circa1883 (Box 38, Folder 70)
    - Rom v 12-21, Exposition of, undated (Box 38, Folder 71)
    - I Cor i: 17-31; viii: 1-13; xiii: 1-13 II Cor xix: 1-15 Critical notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 72)
    - Gal 4: 1-16, Critical notes, 1884 (Box 38, Folder 73)
    - Eph iv:25; vi:1-13, Critical notes and commentary, 1885-1889 (Box 38, Folder 74)
    - Phil ii:5-16, Critical notes, 1885 (Box 38, Folder 75)
    - I Thess iv:13-18. II Thess iii:1-18. I Thess v:1-8 Critical notes, 1884 (Box 38, Folder 76)
    - I Tim i:1-ii:6; II Tim iii:14-iv:8, Critical notes (Box 38, Folder 77)
    - Heb i:1-ii:4; ix:1-12, Critical notes (Box 38, Folder 78)
    - Heb xii: 17, Exposition of, 1885 undated (Box 38, Folder 79)
    - James, Introduction to, undated (Box 38, Folder 80)
    - James i:1-15, Commentary, undated (Box 38, Folder 81)
    - James i:16-27; 3-4, Critical notes, commentary, 1883-1884 (Box 38, Folder 82)
    - II Pet i:1-11, Critical notes, 1885 (Box 38, Folder 83)
  - Theological
    - Atheism, 1847 (Box 38, Folder 84)
    - Authority of Scripture, revelation, miracles, undated (Box 38, Folder 85)
    - Biblical traditions and the mythopoeic process, undated (Box 38, Folder 86)
    - Christianity versus Deism, (Atheism), and Pantheism (delivered before Porter Rhetorical Society), undated (Box 38, Folder 87)
    - Church
      - Church & state relations, undated (Box 38, Folder 88)
      - Church & state relations in the U.S. and colonies, undated (Box 38, Folder 89)
      - History, order, and doctrine, undated (Box 38, Folder 90)
      - Power of the Laity and Prosperity of the Church, 1859 (Box 38, Folder 91)
    - "Historical Argument for Christianity", undated (Box 38, Folder 92)
    - Japan: "A Brief Message to the Thoughtful Classes of Japan", 1880 (Box 38, Folder 93)
    - Meditations and prayers, 1870, undated (Box 38, Folder 94)
    - Monastery of Monte Cassino, undated (Box 38, Folder 95)
    - Morals: "Some Aspects of European Morals" printed, 1882 (Box 38, Folder 96)
    - "Morals, Thoughts on", undated (Box 38, Folder 97)
    - Sin, morality, spirituality, undated (Box 38, Folder 98)
    - Truth, faith, and reason, undated (Box 38, Folder 99)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, undated (Box 38, Folder 100)
  - Bible Revision
    - Committee member list, draft resolution, photograph, 1876, undated (Box 39, Folder 101)
    - "Basis for Study", preliminary issues of various books of New Testament, undated (Box 39, Folder 102)
    - Advanced notes to the Gospels, Acts, Cor., Phil., Col., Thes., James, Dt., undated (Box 39, Folder 103)
    - Information Bulletins (Private), Nos. 1-6, 1875-1877, 1885 (Box 39, Folder 104)
    - First & Provisional Revision
      - Mt.-Lk., undated (Box 39, Folder 105)
      - Jn.-Rom., undated (Box 39, Folder 106)
      - Cor.-Rev., n.d (Box 39, Folder 107)
    - "Apocalypsis Ioanon: New Testament in the Original Greek", undated (Box 40, Folder 108)
    - Changes in the Second Revision, Deviations from the English Second Revision, 1880, undated (Box 40, Folder 109)
    - Suggestions relative to the Second Revision of the Gospels, Vol. I-III, undated (Box 40, Folder 110)
    - Appendix, undated (Box 40, Folder 111)
  - Bible Revision: Related Articles
    - Abbot, Ezra: "The Late Professor Tischendorf", 1875 (Box 40, Folder 112)
    - Abbot, Ezra: "On the Reading 'An Only-begotten God", 1875 (Box 40, Folder 112)
    - Abbot, Ezra: "On Titus ii:13 and II Pet i:1", undated (Box 40, Folder 112)
    - Dwight, Timothy: "The American Appendix", 1881 (Box 40, Folder 113)
    - Shaff, Philip, ed.: "Historical Account of the Work of the American Committee of Revision of the Authorized English Version of the Bible", 1885 (Box 40, Folder 114)
    - Woolsey, T.D.
      - "End of Luke's Gospel and Beginning of Acts", 1882 (Box 40, Folder 115)
      - "On a Passage in Matthew xxvi:50", undated (Box 40, Folder 115)
      - "On the Latin Equivalent of Cyrenius (Lk. 2:2), 1878 (Box 40, Folder 115)
      - History of Early Texts and Translations of the Bible to the Present (MSS) (Box 40, Folder 116)
      - "Reasons for a New Revision of the Scriptures in English" (Box 40, Folder 117)
    - Anon. ("J.A:) (Box 40, Folder 118)
      - "notes on the Gospel of St, Matthew" On the Translation of 'Atonement'", undated (Box 40, Folder 118)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 40, Folder 119)
  - Sermons
    - Gen. v:24; Heb. xi:5-6, 1872 (Box 41, Folder 120)
    - Ex. iii: 11-12, 1854 (Box 41, Folder 120)
    - I Kings xix, 1873 (Box 41, Folder 120)
    - Ps. 8:5, 1871 (Box 41, Folder 121)
    - Ps. 30:5, 88:7, Circa1886 (Box 41, Folder 121)
    - Ps. 32:5 (On Confession), 1869 (Box 41, Folder 121)
    - Ps. 119:9 (Printed), 1866 (Box 41, Folder 121)
    - Proverbs 12:22 "On Lying", 1870 (Box 41, Folder 122)
    - Eccles. 11:1; John i:4 "Mirth and Joy", 1859 (Box 41, Folder 122)
    - Ez. viii:12, 1867 (Box 41, Folder 122)
    - Ez. xxxvi:27 "Value of Spiritual Help", 1869 (Box 41, Folder 122)
    - Matthew 5:8, 1873 (Box 41, Folder 123)
    - Mt. 11:28-30, 1874 (Box 41, Folder 123)
    - Mt. 13:33, 1853 (Box 41, Folder 123)
    - Mt. 19:22, 1866 (Box 41, Folder 123)
    - Mt. 27:43; John 10:17, undated (Box 41, Folder 123)
    - Lk. 10:21, 1862 (Box 41, Folder 124)
    - Lk. 15:11-32, 1855-1856 (Box 41, Folder 124)
    - Lk. 16:4, undated (Box 41, Folder 125)
    - Lk. 19:10, 1873 (Box 41, Folder 125)
    - Lk. 23:39-43, 1852 (Box 41, Folder 125)
    - Jn. 3:8 Christ at Jacob's Well, 1871 (Box 41, Folder 126)
    - Jn. 4:6-42, 1871 (Box 41, Folder 126)
    - Jn. 10:17-18, 1857 (Box 41, Folder 126)
    - Jn. 13:1-17, 1853 (Box 41, Folder 127)
    - Jn. 16:7, 1871 (Box 41, Folder 127)
    - Jn. 24:29 Doubts of Thomas, 1857 (Box 41, Folder 127)
    - Acts 13:22, 1852 (Box 41, Folder 128)
    - Rom 1:20-24 On Polytheism & Idolotry, 1865 (Box 41, Folder 128)
    - Rom 7:15-17, 1872 (Box 41, Folder 128)
    - Rom 8:15 Spirit of Adoption and of Bondage, 1852 (Box 41, Folder 129)
    - I Cor. 1:17, 2:4, 1856 (Box 41, Folder 129)
    - I Cor. 10:13, 1873 (Box 41, Folder 129)
    - I Cor. 10:29+, 1861 (Box 41, Folder 130)
    - I Cor. 14:40, 1863 (Box 41, Folder 130)
    - I Cor. 15:56, 1862 (Box 41, Folder 130)
    - I Cor. 15:56+, undated (Box 41, Folder 130)